Nicolas F. Ovalles

(240) 370-2196 nick.ovalles@gmail.com

Forward-thinking and results-focused Sales leader with a strong working knowledge in operations leadership, budgeting, training, and customer service. With a combined four years of experience overseeing operations of diverse food service and hospitality establishments, I am adaptable in any setting and always looking to learn and grow in my career and help my team grow in their careers.

EXPERIENCE

Natac Group — Sales Account Manager

May 2020 - Present

Market and sell raw natural ingredients to big name companies for the production of nutraceuticals. Attend expos and make introductions, and ensure that all arrangements are set. Research and analyze product specifications. Coordinate with my team in Madrid, Spain on a daily basis. Respond to and try to fulfill any and all leads. Manage 10–15 accounts at one time.

Marriott International, St. Regis Hotel Downtown DC— Catering Sales Coordinator

October 2019 - May 2020

Meet group coordinator/host(ess) prior to functions, make introductions, and ensure that all arrangements are agreeable. Read and analyze banquet event order in order to gather guest information, determine proper set up, timeline, specific guest needs, buffets, action stations, etc. Respond to and try to fulfill any special banquet event arrangements. Follow up on special banquet event arrangements to ensure compliance.

Marriott International, Renaissance Hotel Downtown DC— Engineering Admin

January 2019 – October 2019

Maintained a \$150,000/month budget for the department. Championed all procurement processes. Managed and facilitated all contracts for the department. Co-led the Team to be the #1 Engineering Dept. on the East Coast and Top 10 in the Nation. Oversaw all office, administrative, and employee needs.

SKILLS

Foreign Languages

Project Management

Verbal and Written
Communication

Financial Management

Computer Proficiency (Word, Excel, PPT, etc)

Marriott Hot Shop Proficiency

CERTIFICATIONS

ISPT 2018 Certification

Peer Review Panelist (12/2018)

Power Facilitation Training (12/2018)

TiPS Certification

AWARDS

Stephen Decatur Award (Surface Navy Association)

SGA President of the Year (Montgomery County Public Schools)

Academic Dean's List

Eagle Scout Award

LANGUAGES

English (fluent), Spanish (fluent), Portuguese (intermediate), ASL (intermediate)

Marriott International, Bethesda North Marriott Hotel— Front Office/Food & Beverage Operations

June 2018 - January 2019

Serving, cleaning, and interacting with guests in Concierge Lounge, Moderate Admin work, assisting guests with luggage and enhancing their check in experience. Led bar program, implemented and maintained restaurant/bar service expectations, oversaw 40 associates, scheduling, hiring and staff training.

Marriott International, Renaissance Hotel Downtown DC— Human Resource Coordinator

October 2017 - June 2018

Office Work, Employee Relations and communications, translating, assisting with Payroll administration, filing, Data Entry, etc.

The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, Orem, Utah— Full-Time Missionary

October 2015 - October 2017

Full-Time religious proselytizing mission. One-on-One teaching, and assisted in Office work, scheduling events and venues, touring the Mission for training other leaders and missionaries.

EDUCATION

University of Maryland— Bachelor of Science

January 2018 - Present

Bachelor of Science Candidate 2022, International Relations

Montgomery College — General Studies

January 2018 - December 2018

General Studies Credits. Coursework ranges from Arts to Critical Science.